Daniel Schorr Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Daniel Schorr Papers 1922-2010 (bulk 1943-2006)
MSS85407
Schorr, Daniel, 1916-2010
68,000 items
194 containers plus 3 oversize
78 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Print and broadcast journalist. Broadcast scripts, articles and book production material, correspondence, speeches, and printed material relating to Schorr's career in journalism.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Adenauer, Konrad, 1876-1967.; Blackmun, Harry A. (Harry Andrew), 1908-1999--Correspondence.; Castro, Fidel, 1926-2016.; Colson, Charles W.--Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Friendly, Alfred (Captain)--Correspondence.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994--Correspondence.; Paley, William S. (William Samuel), 1901-1990--Correspondence.; Salant, Richard S., -1993--Correspondence.; Schorr, Daniel, 1916-2010.; Schorr, Daniel, 1916-2010. Staying tuned: a life in journalism. 2001.; Schorr, Tillie Godiner--Correspondence.; Stern, Isaac, 1920-2001.; Turner, Ted--Correspondence.; Wouk, Herman, 1915-2019--Correspondence.
Organizations
Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies.; Aspen Institute.; Cable News Network.; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.; Marshall Plan.; National Public Radio (U.S.); North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; United States. Central Intelligence Agency.; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation.
Subjects
Civil rights.; Cold War.; Environmental policy.; Freedom of speech.; Intelligence service--United States.; Journalism.; Persian Gulf War, 1991.; Political corruption--United States.; Reconstruction (1939-1951); Summit meetings.; Urban policy.; Watergate Affair, 1972-1974.; World politics.; World War, 1939-1945--Military intelligence--United States.
Places
Berlin (Germany)--History--Blockade, 1948-1949.; Camp Polk (La.); Fort Sam Houston (Tex.); Middle East--Foreign relations--United States.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--United States.; Soviet Union--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Foreign relations--20th century.; United States--Foreign relations--Middle East.; United States--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.
Occupations
Journalists.
Provenance
The papers of Daniel Schorr, print and broadcast journalist, were given to the Library of Congress by Schorr in 2008. An addition was given by his wife, Lisbeth Bamberger Schorr, in 2010.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Some photographs and slides have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. Video and audio recordings have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Daniel Schorr Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Daniel Schorr are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1916, Aug. 31 Born, New York, N.Y.
1930 1933 Attended DeWitt Clinton High School, New York, N. Y.
1934 1941 Reporter, Jewish Daily Bulletin and Jewish Telegraphic Agency, New York, N.Y.
1939 Bachelor's degree, City College of New York, New York, N.Y.
1943 1945 Sergeant, United States Army
1946 1947 News editor, Aneta (Netherlands news agency), New York, N.Y., then Amsterdam, Netherlands
1948 1953 Stringer reporter, Christian Science Monitor, New York Times, American Broadcasting Co., Columbia Broadcasting System, and other media, Amsterdam, Netherlands
1950 Awarded first William the Silent Award, Hague, Netherlands
1953 1955 Diplomatic correspondent, Columbia Broadcasting System
1955 1957 Correspondent, Moscow Bureau, Columbia Broadcasting System, Moscow, Union of Soviet Socialist Republics
1958 1960 Diplomatic correspondent, Columbia Broadcasting System
1960 1966 Chief, Germany and Eastern Europe Bureau, Columbia Broadcasting System, Bonn, Germany
1966 Married Lisbeth Bamberger
1966 1976 Reporter-correspondent, Washington Bureau, Columbia Broadcasting System, Washington, D.C.
1970 Published Don't Get Sick in America. Nashville: Aurora Publishers
1972 Awarded Emmy Award (also in 1973 and 1974)
1976 1979 Regents Professor of Journalism, University of California, Berkeley, Calif.
1977 Published Clearing the Air. Boston: Houghton Mifflin
1979 1985 News analyst, Cable News Network, Washington, D.C.
1985 2010 Senior news analyst, National Public Radio, Washington, D.C.
1996 Awarded “Golden Baton,” Alfred I. Dupont-Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
2001 Published Staying Tuned: A Life in Journalism. New York: Simon and Schuster Pocket Books
2002 Awarded Edward R. Murrow Award for Lifetime Achievement in Broadcasting
2010, July 23 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The Daniel Schorr Papers (1916-2010) span the years 1922-2010, with the bulk of the material dating from 1943 to 2006. The papers are organized into the following series: Family and Personal File, Correspondence, Broadcasts and Film, Speeches and Public Appearances, Writings File, Subject File, Miscellany, 2017 Addition, Oversize.
The Family and Personal File contains biographical material, professional achievement awards, and estate, financial, and military records. The correspondence consists chiefly of Schorr's letters to his mother, Tillie Godiner Schorr. They describe his activities as a United States Army intelligence officer stationed at Camp Polk, Louisiana, and Fort Sam Houston, San Antonio, Texas, during World War II. In later years the letters provide details of his life and work in postwar Europe into the Cold War era. In addition to politics, Schorr also covered cultural events. His friendship with violinist Isaac Stern is well documented. The diaries and notebooks contain Schorr's observations while on news reporting assignments.
The Correspondence series contains incoming and copies of outgoing letters to professional colleagues, friends, and fans. Chief correspondents are Harry A. Blackmun, Charles W. Colson, Captain Alfred Friendly, Richard M. Nixon, William S. Paley, Richard S. Salant, Ted Turner, and Herman Wouk.
The Broadcasts and Film series forms the centerpiece of the papers. Although incorporating contracts, correspondence, and publicity material, most of the series consists of scripts written primarily for Cable News Network, Columbia Broadcasting System, and National Public Radio. European events covered include postwar reconstruction, the Marshall Plan, the creation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, superpower summit meetings, Moscow under Nikita Sergeevich Khrushchev, and the Berlin crisis of 1961. Individuals receiving coverage by Schorr were Khrushchev, Konrad Adenauer, Fidel Castro, and Dwight D. Eisenhower. In the United States, Schorr reported on issues relating to civil rights, urban problems, and the environment. He is particularly known for his investigation of the Watergate Affair and scandals involving the Central Intelligence Agency and the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The papers document his clash with CBS and the United States House of Representatives over his publication of a suppressed intelligence report.
The Speeches and Public Appearances series documents Schorr's activities on the professional lecture circuit as a keynote speaker, as well as a classroom lecturer, conference participant, and panel moderator. He regularly participated in the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies (later the Aspen Institute) in Aspen, Colorado. Material includes background information, contracts, correspondence, notes, publicity, and texts of speeches.
The Writings File includes production material for Schorr's books, Clearing the Air, Don't Get Sick in America, and Staying Tuned: A Life in Journalism. Schorr's career as a print journalist is represented by clippings and typescripts of articles written for newspapers and magazines. The topics duplicate those covered in his broadcasts.
The Subject File contains Schorr's reference material for his writings and broadcasts, chiefly news clippings, reports, and printed material.
The Miscellany series consists of legal case material regarding freedom of speech issues, Schorr's press passes, and a set of National Public Radio playing cards featuring its journalists.
The 2017 Addition series spans the years 1939 to 2010, with the bulk of the material dating between 1986 and 1990. The series complements the initial portion of the collection and relates to Schorr's career as a print and broadcast journalist. The material is arranged in five groups: broadcasts and film, correspondence, family and personal file, miscellany, and writings. The majority of the 2017 Addition consists of scripts of Schorr's regular commentary on National Public Radio (NPR) as a senior news analyst, including appearances on Weekend Edition, All Things Considered, The Two-Way, and a special call-in program initiated in 1991 at the onset of the Gulf War. The period 1986 to 1991 is particularly well documented, though scripts date throughout the tenure of Schorr's career at NPR, from 1985 until his death in 2010. Many of the scripts in this series overlap with those in the Broadcasts and Film series, though many of the scripts contained here include Schorr's edits and annotations. Also included are several iterations of the script for Watergate, a television miniseries narrated by Schorr in 1994. The writings file contains clippings of articles authored by Schorr for various serial publications, as well as a copy of his manuscript for Staying Tuned: A Life in Journalism.
The Oversize series includes awards, certificates, and posters.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in nine series:
Family and Personal File, 1922-2004
Correspondence, 1932-2006
Broadcasts and Film, 1948-2006
Speeches and Public Appearances, 1956-2006
Writings File, 1934-2005
Subject File, 1933-2004
Miscellany, 1960-1994
2017 Addition, 1939-2010
Oversize, 1926-2001
Container List
- Family and Personal File, 1922-2004 (Box 1-14)
  Awards, certificates, biographical and genealogical information, family correspondence, diaries and notebooks, estate and financial records, military records, school papers, and travel papers.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Awards and certificates, 1926-1933, 1942, 1950-1951, 1957, 1967-1984, 1994-2000 See also Oversize, (7 folders) (Box 1)
  - Biographical information (Box 1)
    - Articles, 1944, 1950-1989, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - Articles, 1944, 1950-1989, (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - Cartoons, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Genealogical material, 1963, 1992-2002, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Oral history transcript, 1978, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - 1943-1945, (10 folders) (Box 3)
    - 1946-1956, (18 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1957-1976, 1986-2001, undated, (7 folders) (Box 5)
  - Diaries and notebooks (Box 5)
    - 1934, 1942-1958, (3 folders)
    - 1955-1957, (5 folders) (Box 6)
    - 1957, (1 folder) (Box 6)
    - 1957, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - 1957-1961, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - 1960-1967, (7 folders) (Box 8)
    - 1968-1975, (7 folders) (Box 9)
    - 1975-1986, (8 folders) (Box 10)
    - 1984-1992, 2004, undated, (6 folders) (Box 11)
  - Estate records (Box 11)
    - Trust funds, 1969, 1977-1983, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Wills, 1969, 1982-1989, (3 folders) (Box 12)
  - Financial records (Box 12)
    - 1949-1951, 1966-1978, (6 folders) (Box 12)
    - 1979-1986, (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Military records, 1943-1945, undated, (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Miscellany (Box 13)
    - Appointment calendar, 1976 (Box 13)
    - Birthdays (Box 13)
      - 1976, 1986-1996, (4 folders) (Box 13)
      - 2001 (Box 14)
    - Printed matter, 1941-1946, 1957-1961, 1975-1976 (Box 14)
    - Wedding, 1967 (Box 14)
  - School papers, 1926-1932, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Schorr, Tillie, 1922, 1948, 1954-1955, 1963-1964, 1970-1976, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Travel papers (Box 14)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1982 (Box 14)
    - Miscellany, 1988-1993 (Box 14)
    - Passports, 1946-1981 (Box 14)
- Correspondence, 1932-2006 (Box 14-21)
  Incoming and copies of outgoing correspondence with colleagues.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Abrams, Floyd, 1978-1983 (Box 14)
  - Adas Israel Congregation, Washington, D.C., 1979-1984 (Box 14)
  - American Broadcasting Co., 1985-1986 (Box 14)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1977-1982 (Box 14)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., 1991 (Box 15)
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1971, 1977-1985, 1992-1996, 2006 (Box 15)
  - Bayh, Birch, 1977-1979 (Box 15)
  - Blackmun, Harry A., 1982-1994 (Box 15)
  - Bloch, Lucille, 1989-1993 (Box 15)
  - Boorstin, Daniel J., 1977-1982 (Box 15)
  - Bush, George W., 1978, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Bybee, Jay S., 1992 (Box 15)
  - “B” miscellaneous, 1953, 1960, 1973-1994 (Box 15)
  - Caplain and Drysdale, 1988-1990 (Box 15)
  - Center for Investigative Reporting, San Francisco, Calif., 1993-1996 (Box 15)
  - City College of New York, New York, N.Y., 1977-1978, 1985-1996, 2004 (Box 15)
  - Colby, William E., 1978 (Box 15)
  - Colson, Charles W., 1976-1978, 1994 (Box 15)
  - “C” miscellaneous, 1962, 1972-1990, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Daily Mail, 1949-1950 (Box 15)
  - Daniel, Clifton, 1983 (Box 15)
  - Davis, Michael K., 1990 (Box 15)
  - Davis, Nathaniel, 1975-1983 (Box 15)
  - Des Moines Register and Tribune, 1976-1980, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - DeWitt Clinton High School, New York, N.Y., 1932, 1988-1999 (Box 16)
  - Doder, Dusko, 1992-1995 (Box 16)
  - Duke University, Durham, N.C., 1980-1982 (Box 16)
  - “D” miscellaneous, 1964-1968, 1975-1992 (Box 16)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1992-1997 (Box 16)
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1975-1985 (Box 16)
  - Fein, Rashi, 1977-1978 (Box 16)
  - Forbes, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Ford, Gerald R., 1977 (Box 16)
  - Fortas, Abe, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Freedom of information requests (Box 16)
    - 1972-1976, (3 folders) (Box 16)
    - 1978, undated, (5 folders) (Box 17)
  - Friendly, Fred W., 1966, 1974-1983, 1991-1998 (Box 17)
  - Friends of Tregaron, Washington, D.C., 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - Fuchs, Lawrence H., 1985 (Box 17)
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1972-1985, 1997 (Box 17)
  - Gordey, Beverly and Michael, 1977-1983, 1989 (Box 18)
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1962, 1976-1986, 1992 (Box 18)
  - Harris, Irving Brooks, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Harry Walker, Inc., 1965, 1982-1988 (Box 18)
  - Heywood Broun Award Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Hind, Rick, 1976-1978 (Box 18)
  - Hoch, Paul L., 1975-1978, 1991-1992 (Box 18)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1966 (Box 18)
  - “H” miscellaneous, 1969-1992 (Box 18)
  - Index on Censorship, 1976-1978 (Box 18)
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1978, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Jewish Museum, Jewish National Archive of Broadcasting, New York, N.Y., 1984-1986 (Box 18)
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1971, 1977-1986, 1996, 2002 (Box 18)
  - Kalb, Marvin, 1965, 1994-1999 (Box 18)
  - Kennedy, Edward Moore, 1992 (Box 18)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1977-1984 (Box 18)
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1960-1965, 1977-1982, 1990-1993 (Box 18)
  - Laitin, Joseph, 1988, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Lear, Norman, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Leigh Bureau, 1957-1979 (Box 19)
  - Los Angeles Times, 1976 (Box 19)
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1973-1982, 1989-1990 (Box 19)
  - Mankiewicz, Frank, 1992 (Box 19)
  - McFarlane, Robert C., 1988-1994, 2001 (Box 19)
  - McGovern, George, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Morton L. Janklow Associates, 1977-1980 (Box 19)
  - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1980-1981 (Box 19)
  - “M” miscellaneous, 1961, 1974-1992 (Box 19)
  - New Israel Fund, 1986-1988 (Box 19)
  - New Republic, 1977-1981 (Box 19)
  - New York Times, 1952, 1966-1987, (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - New York University, New York, N.Y., 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1984, 1991-1994 (Box 20)
  - “N” miscellaneous, 1978-1982, 1988 (Box 20)
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1976-1979, 1994, 2000-2001 (Box 20)
  - Powell, Colin L., 1992 (Box 20)
  - Progressive, 1977-1994 (Box 20)
  - Prouty, L. Fletcher, 1976-1977 (Box 20)
  - “P” miscellaneous, 1975-1991, 1997 (Box 20)
  - “Q” miscellaneous, 1993 (Box 20)
  - Rather, Dan, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Rolling Stone, 1975-1977 (Box 20)
  - “R” miscellaneous, 1977-1990 (Box 20)
  - Salant, Richard S., 1969, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Schiller, G. Peter, 1980, 1990-1991 (Box 20)
  - Shriver, Sargent, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Simon and Schuster, 1978 (Box 20)
  - “S” miscellaneous, 1969, 1975-1984, 1999 (Box 20)
  - Time-Life International, 1948-1949 (Box 21)
  - Turner, Ted, 1985 (Box 21)
  - TV Guide, 1960-1961, 1976, 1989-1991 (Box 21)
  - “T” miscellaneous, 1971-1982, 1989-1992 (Box 21)
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1973-1980 (Box 21)
  - Vrij Nederland, 1977-1983 (Box 21)
  - “V” miscellaneous, 1947, 1966, 1978-1979, 2000-2001 (Box 21)
  - Washington Post, 1957, 1976-1980 (Box 21)
  - Worthy, William, 1954, 1960, 1967-1970, 1982-1985 (Box 21)
  - Wouk, Herman, 1979-1981 (Box 21)
  - “W” miscellaneous, 1966-1967, 1975-2002 (Box 21)
  - “Y” miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Zappa, Frank, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - “Z” miscellaneous, 1976-1980 (Box 21)
  - Unidentified, 1973-1974, 1980-1986 (Box 21)
- Broadcasts and Film, 1948-2006 (Box 21-93)
  Contracts, correspondence, publicity, and scripts.
  Arranged alphabetically by network, sponsor, or project.
  - American Broadcasting Co., 1948, 1977-1985, (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Aspen Center for Public Radio, Aspen, Colo., 1980-1981 (Box 21)
  - British Broadcasting Corp., 1979, 1992 (Box 21)
  - Cable News Network (Box 22)
    - Ask CNN, 1984-1985 (Box 22)
    - Contracts, 1979-1985, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, 1980-2000, undated, (4 folders) (Box 22)
    - Crossfire, 1992-1994 (Box 22)
    - Desk of Daniel Schorr (Box 22)
      - 1981-1982, (4 folders) (Box 22)
      - 1983, (6 folders) (Box 23)
      - 1984 (Box 23)
        - Jan.-June, (4 folders) (Box 23)
        - July-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 24)
      - 1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - Expense reports, 1980-1985, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Miscellany, 1984, undated (Box 24)
    - Newsmaker (Box 25)
      - 1980 (Box 25)
      - 1981 (Box 25)
        - Jan.-Nov., (6 folders) (Box 25)
        - Dec. (Box 26)
      - 1982 (Box 26)
        - Jan.-Sept., (6 folders) (Box 26)
        - Oct.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - 1983, (5 folders) (Box 27)
      - 1984 (Box 27)
        - Jan.-Apr., (2 folders) (Box 27)
        - May-June (Box 28)
    - Newswatch, 1981-1983, undated, (10 folders) (Box 28)
    - Postscript and other programs (Box 29)
      - 1980, (8 folders) (Box 29)
      - 1981 (Box 29)
        - Jan.-Apr., (3 folders) (Box 29)
        - May-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 30)
      - 1982, (2 folders) (Box 30)
      - 1983 (Box 30)
        - Jan.-Mar. (Box 30)
        - Apr.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 31)
      - 1984-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Publicity (Box 31)
      - 1973-1984, (6 folders) (Box 31)
      - 1985-2000 (Box 32)
    - Script index, 1980-1981 (Box 32)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (Box 32)
    - Contracts, 1969-1976 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence (Box 32)
      - 1956-1975, (6 folders) (Box 32)
      - 1976 (Box 32)
        - Jan. (Box 32)
        - Feb., (8 folders) (Box 33)
        - Mar.-Aug., (9 folders) (Box 34)
        - Sept.-Oct., (11 folders) (Box 35)
        - Nov.-Dec. (Box 36)
      - 1977-1981, undated, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Diplomatic correspondent (Box 36)
      - Berlin, Germany, 1958-1959, (2 folders) (Box 36)
      - Cuba, 1960 (Box 36)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D., trips (Box 36)
        - India, 1959 (Box 36)
        - South America, 1960 (Box 36)
      - Geneva, Switzerland, 1959-1960, (4 folders) (Box 36)
      - Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, trips (Box 37)
        - Austria, 1960 (Box 37)
        - Finland, 1957 (Box 37)
        - France, 1960, (2 folders) (Box 37)
        - United Nations, 1960 (Box 37)
        - United States, 1959 (Box 37)
      - Little Rock, Ark., 1958 (Box 37)
      - Oslo, Norway, 1961 (Box 37)
      - Paris, France, 1958-1959 (Box 37)
      - Poland, 1958-1959, (3 folders) (Box 37)
      - Refugee camps in Europe, 1955 (Box 37)
      - Soviet Union, 1958-1959 (Box 38)
      - United Nations, Middle East crisis, 1958 (Box 38)
    - Freelance reporter, 1949-1953, (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Germany and Eastern Europe Bureau, Bonn, Germany (Box 38)
      - Adenauer, Konrad, 1960-1967, undated, (5 folders) (Box 38)
      - Budapest, Hungary, 1961-1965 (Box 38)
      - Bulgaria, 1965 (Box 38)
      - Cyprus, 1964 (Box 38)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1964-1965, (1 folder) (Box 38)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1964-1965, (1 folder) (Box 39)
      - Espionage, 1962, 1968 (Box 39)
      - Geneva, Switzerland, 1961-1965, (3 folders) (Box 39)
      - Germany (Box 39)
        - 1960, (4 folders) (Box 39)
        - 1961 (Box 40)
          - Jan.-Sept., (7 folders) (Box 40)
          - Oct.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 41)
        - 1962 (Box 41)
          - Jan.-June, (6 folders) (Box 41)
          - July-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 42)
        - 1963 (Box 42)
          - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders) (Box 42)
          - Mar.-Sept., (8 folders) (Box 43)
          - Oct.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box 44)
        - 1964 (Box 44)
          - Jan.-May, (5 folders) (Box 44)
          - June-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 45)
        - 1965 (Box 45)
          - Jan.-Sept., (8 folders) (Box 45)
          - Oct.-Nov. (Box 46)
        - 1966, (2 folders) (Box 46)
      - Greece, 1965 (Box 46)
      - Romania, 1964 (Box 46)
      - Vienna, Austria, 1960-1966, (3 folders) (Box 46)
    - Miscellany, 1966-1976 (Box 46)
    - Moscow Bureau, Moscow, Soviet Union (Box 46)
      - Correspondence, 1955-1957, (5 folders) (Box 46)
      - Notes, 1955-1957, (5 folders) (Box 47)
      - Publicity, 1956-1958 (Box 47)
      - Schedules, 1956 (Box 47)
      - Scripts (Box 47)
        - 1955, (5 folders) (Box 47)
        - 1956, (11 folders) (Box 48)
        - 1957 (Box 49)
          - Jan.-Oct., (14 folders) (Box 49)
          - Nov.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 50)
    - Special reports and programs (Box 50)
      - A Boy Named Terry Egan See also Containers 55-56, What Are We Doing to Our Children?
        - Background information, 1972-1973, (3 folders) (Box 50)
        - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 50)
        - Publicity, 1973 (Box 50)
        - Scripts, 1973 (Box 50)
      - Cleveland, Ohio, 1967 (Box 50)
      - Colby of the CIA, 1976 (Box 51)
      - Colson, Charles W., interview, 1975-1976 (Box 51)
      - The Day They Had to Close the Schools, 1970 (Box 51)
      - Dinah! 1976-1977 (Box 51)
      - East Europe: Satellites Out of Orbit, 1964-1965 (Box 51)
      - East Germany: The land Beyond the Wall (Box 51)
        - Background information, 1961-1962 (Box 51)
        - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 51)
        - Publicity, 1962 (Box 51)
        - Scripts, 1961, (3 folders) (Box 51)
      - Haldeman: The Nixon Years, 1975 (Box 52)
      - Health in America, 1970 (Box 52)
      - The Poisoned Air, 1966 (Box 52)
      - Prescription: Take with Caution, 1974-1975 (Box 52)
      - The President Abroad: A Trip to a Communist Capital, 1969 (Box 52)
      - The President Resigns, 1974 (Box 52)
      - Romania, 1964, (4 folders) (Box 52)
      - See It Now, Poland, 1957 (Box 52)
      - Small World, 1960 (Box 52)
      - Terrorism, undated (Box 53)
      - Title I education funds, 1967 (Box 53)
      - Twentieth Century (Box 53)
        - “Hungary Today,” 1956-1961, (2 folders) (Box 53)
        - “Man with a Violin: Isaac Stern,” 1965, (2 folders) (Box 53)